# JOSEPH JOHNSON II

TECH SAVVY | DATA ANALYTICS | NETWORK ADMINISTRATION | TEAM LEADERSHIP | RESEARCH | HACKER-U 📞 310.735.3839

# • DETAILS •

310.735.3839 captainixamikazegaming@gmail.com

# SKILLS

Computer Skills

**Computer Networking** 

Microsoft Excel

Adaptability

**Customer Service** 

Microsoft Office

Communication Skills

Fast Learner

Leadership Skills

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Ability to Work in a Team

# PROFILE

Strategic, creative, and data-driven professional with more than 7 years of experience with high level and diverse national and international projects, offering a unique blend of Technical understanding and interpersonal communication skills to propel the workforce into a more secure network and overall work experience.

### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Operations Specialist at VeoRide, Signal Hill

March 2021 — Present

- Follow the mobile App instruction to complete shift tasks
- Drive a company's van to find scooters and swap battery
- Rebalance scooters from low demand to high demand areas
- Perform basic repair and quality check
- Respond to on-demand requests to locate/retrieve scooters
- · Assist with other tasks assigned by Operations Manager

# Remote IT Support at Centene, Woodland Hills

March 2020 — March 2021

- install and configure computer hardware operating systems and applications
- monitor and maintain computer systems and networks
- talk staff or clients through a series of actions, over the phone, to help set up systems or resolve issues
- troubleshoot system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults
- provide support, including procedural documentation and relevant reports
- follow diagrams and written instructions to repair a fault or set up a system
- support the roll-out of new applications
- set up new users' accounts and profiles and deal with password issues
- · respond within agreed time limits to call-outs
- test and evaluate new technologies to benefit the company
- · conduct electrical safety checks on computer equipment

# Field Service Technician II at Cubic Transportations system Inc., Norwalk, San Diego, San Francisco

September 2018 — March 2020

- Reads and interpret complex schematics, engineering drawings, work orders, technical manuals, and specifications.
- Initializes and determines readiness of electronic devices for correct operations.
- Analyzes and interprets device operations for malfunctions, replace spares, troubleshoot faults after isolation and repair modules with component parts.
- Prepares and maintains appropriate and required records.
- Performs other related duties as required.

### Sr Network Admin/Helpdesk/IT&Cust. Support at Staycation Co., Venice

February 2016 — June 2018

- Researching and recommending upgrades to software and hardware and scheduling them to minimize downtime and maximize over performance and stability within the networks server.
- Testing all systems to make sure they are performing at optimal levels while investigating any issues.

- Analyzing website performance to ascertain its usability and improve the customer experience.
- Demonstrates proficiency in AWS, a <u>cloud computing</u> platform from Amazon that provides customers with a wide array of <u>cloud</u> services, Such as Amazon Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (<u>Amazon EC2</u>), Amazon Simple Storage Service (<u>Amazon S3</u>), Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (<u>Amazon VPC</u>), <u>Amazon SimpleDB</u> and <u>Amazon WorkSpaces</u>.

### Recruiter at Randstad, Torrence

February 2015 — February 2016

- Develops, facilitates, and implements all phases of the recruitment process.
- Collaborates with department managers to identify and draft detailed and accurate job descriptions and hiring criteria.
- Identifies and implements efficient and effective recruiting methods and strategies based on the available role, industry standards, and the needs of the organization.
- · Screens applications and selects qualified candidates.
- Schedules interviews; oversees preparation of interview questions and other hiring and selection materials.
- Assists with the interview process, attending and conducting interviews with managers, directors, and other stakeholders.
- Collaborates with the hiring manager and/or other human resource staff during the offer process, identifying and recommending salary ranges, incentives, start dates, and other pertinent details.
- Ensures compliance with federal, state, and local employment laws and regulations, and company policies.
- Attends and participates in college job fairs and recruiting sessions.
- demonstrates proficeny in JazzHR, Taleo, & Zendesk

### Helpdesk at Youtube Space LA, Playa vista

October 2012 — January 2015

- Monitor and respond quickly to incoming requests relate to IT issues.
- Maintain computer systems and act as support if any system goes down.
- Responsible for PC's, Printers, Servers and related equipment (monitor, keyboard, mouse, hard drive, etc).
- Maintain user PCs, including upgrades and configuration as needed.
- Keep inventory of all equipment, software, and license users.
- Install, configure, and upgrade PC software.

# EDUCATION

HS Diploma, Edward R. Roybal LC, Los Angeles

February 2009 — June 2012

Some Credit, UC Davis, Davis

June 2013 — September 2013

Associates Of Science Computer Network & Security Management , West La College, West Los Angeles

June 2014 — June 2016

# COURSES

CyberSecurity Professional, California State University Long Beach May 2021 — Present

### HONORABLE MENTION

Cyber Patriot Ethical hacking Program at Edward R. Roybal LC, Los Angeles March 2010 — July 2013

National Youth Cyber Defense Competition challenges teams of high school and middle school students to find and fix cybersecurity vulnerabilities in virtual operating systems. Using a proprietary competition system, teams are scored on how secure they make the system

UCLA Sat. Programming Academy at UCLA, West Los Angeles

May 2010 — July 2012